<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog</id>
    <title>Area-27 Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Area-27 Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[April]]></title>
        <id>https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog/april</id>
        <link href="https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog/april"/>
        <updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What a crazy month its been aye? Today I had a huge meeting with the team and we've gotten some really cool idea's going! I also finally got our budget approved for the next 6 months, which should hopefully help the team as an incentive.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>April</h1><p>What a crazy month its been aye? Today I had a huge meeting with the team and we've gotten some really cool idea's going! I also finally got our budget approved for the next 6 months, which should hopefully help the team as an incentive.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="water-filtration">Water Filtration<a href="#water-filtration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Water Filtration" title="Direct link to Water Filtration">​</a></h2><p>I wanted the barrels to be physics based, for those who tuned into my last stream you wouldve seen me trying to figure this out, of course, its a much harder task than youd expect but I found a pretty cool way to do it with some constraints and other parts to stop the barrel from going off course, as you can see in the video below</p><video width="800" height="400" controls=""><source src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/50265734/232625222-712f1cdb-53b0-48b1-9554-0b943114b9f6.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video><p>I also wanted the rope that picks up the barrels to be as dynamic and nice looking as possible, this isnt your regular old rope constraint, the code changes the length dynamically to give it that swinging look</p><video width="800" height="400" controls=""><source src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/50265734/232626496-3819cefb-296e-4a43-802f-e90a6e932e1e.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video><p>Please note this isnt refined yet. <strong>The barrels will not be spawning as fast as you see there.</strong> There's still some things i'd like to iron out with it, and the math for all the filtration has been a nightmare. (I could probably create an actually water filtration system in real life at this point)</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="build">Build<a href="#build" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Build" title="Direct link to Build">​</a></h2><p>The new rebuild has been going great, here's some images of how things started for one of the sectors</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/994064234373726209/1095765726914158592/e00bab8f828752989ab27b2847178128.png" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" src="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/994064234373726209/1095778284282847373/c0c5b249dd6e5113a7b6b56c1ab3eaa8.png" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" src="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/994064234373726209/1095778284555468920/c5c238229c84a4a696c0a1d7dacf5688.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong><em>And now, it looks like this</em></strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/994064234373726209/1097584516354285609/d5028d32a16c655e2be4e77c9e00f65c.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We're also working on pushing the run-down feel so BO2 put this together too</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/994064234373726209/1097578055150620742/53c2366142c749c90fbac0d841345b81.png" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="keep-in-mind-none-of-these-are-final-product-and-are-due-to-be-revised">KEEP IN MIND NONE OF THESE ARE FINAL PRODUCT AND ARE DUE TO BE REVISED<a href="#keep-in-mind-none-of-these-are-final-product-and-are-due-to-be-revised" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to KEEP IN MIND NONE OF THESE ARE FINAL PRODUCT AND ARE DUE TO BE REVISED" title="Direct link to KEEP IN MIND NONE OF THESE ARE FINAL PRODUCT AND ARE DUE TO BE REVISED">​</a></h3><p>Honestly I wish I had more for you, but sadly I don't really. According to the other scripters on the project, there's currently a studio bug not allowing them to play test the game, we've tried to submit bug reports but Bt hasnt been able to due to some restricitions from the site. (Hence why no teaser)</p><p>I do have one more thing though . . . some ideas.</p><p>We plan on implementing a tram system. We had this idea years ago right after v2 came out, but we decided to scrap it due to issue's with how SCP's would breach between sectors, travel lag, etc, but after today's meeting the whole team was able to come up with an innovative way to make that all happen. I would share the models and some of the build but im still trying to make sure we actually own the tram models and don't want to share images until im 100% sure, but as soon as I know ill post again showing what they look like and what the track looks like.</p><p>Im also going to be doing a weekly, or bi-weekly depending on the difficulty, SCP showing, were I show a fully scripted SCP. The model may be the same as 47 for some, but none of the code is shared on the SCP's between 47 and 27, so you'll be seeing something completley new!</p><p>Thats all I have, with the new budget im sure things will move much quicker, especially since there's now more money that can be poured into comissions for smaller systems.</p><p>Thats all I have for now, but I hope this is enough to hold you all over! See ya soon!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Long (Thomastrainiac)</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/thomastrainiac</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="development update" term="development update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://thomastrainiac.github.io/Area-27-Development/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope you're as excited for this as we are!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>I hope you're as excited for this as we are!</strong></p><p>I've been trying to set something like this up for some time now and im glad that its finally here!</p><p>This is where we will keep updates on development, as well as non development related things.</p><p>After reading through that google form I now understand all of the issues i've been presented with and really took it to heart, which is why . . .</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="going-forward">Going Forward<a href="#going-forward" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Going Forward" title="Direct link to Going Forward">​</a></h2><p>From now on you will all know the current track of development, exactly whats going on. Im going to keep images more to the teaser channel in the discord but im going to keep everything else here.</p><p>There will be a post once or twice a week with updates on current progress in stuff, ill also be creating an FAQ section on here, and ill make a post once its completed. I wanted to make sure I got this out to you all first!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="questions-ive-gotten">Questions I've gotten<a href="#questions-ive-gotten" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Questions I've gotten" title="Direct link to Questions I've gotten">​</a></h2><p>Here im just going to answer some questions I got from the form.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="when-is-the-revamp-releasing">When is the revamp releasing?<a href="#when-is-the-revamp-releasing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to When is the revamp releasing?" title="Direct link to When is the revamp releasing?">​</a></h3><p>Im going to give you my completely honest answer, I don't know.</p><p>And it's not that type of answer where im just saying that to be rude, it's just too early to give an estimate that I can confidentally stick to.</p><p>Life happens, a developer may get sick and be unable to work for a few days, roblox does an update that breaks something, we find a major bug and need to go back to fix it, etc, etc.</p><p>I'd love to give you an estimate but im going to wait until im sure of it. The past runners of this project have given multiple empty promises of release, even I did it once with the executives.</p><p>Until im sure beyond a reasonable doubt that my estimate is legit, im keeping quiet about a release.</p><p>But, im still going to take you all on the ride with us from now on, almost <em>every step of the way.</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="revamp-streams">Revamp Streams?<a href="#revamp-streams" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Revamp Streams?" title="Direct link to Revamp Streams?">​</a></h3><p>Honestly its hard to determine what I <em>can</em> stream, not when. Im afraid of showing something I shouldnt on the stream development wise, I want this game to come out and for players to experiance something new, not play the game they saw in screenshots and have everything already be told to them.</p><p>I will however be picking up on streams, my last VOD should be up from twitch, but when I do stream you can find me <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thomastrainiac" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here.</a></p><hr><p>These are quite literally what basically all of the responses were asking about.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whats-going-on-right-now">Whats going on right now?<a href="#whats-going-on-right-now" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whats going on right now?" title="Direct link to Whats going on right now?">​</a></h2><p>This section will be on every blog post, im going to put whats currently being worked on.</p><p>There may be some things not listed to keep it secret but anything that I can tell you I will tell you. These will be updated on the post.</p><p>This will later change to its own page but until I have that done this will work for now.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="water-filtration-system">Water Filtration System<a href="#water-filtration-system" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Water Filtration System" title="Direct link to Water Filtration System">​</a></h2><p>As majroty of you know <strong>Area-27 Revamp</strong> will have a water filtration system for E&amp;T and LD.</p><p>The basic functions of this are keeping the water clean from contaminants that may be in the water</p><p>There will be a crane used to get whatever may be in the water out</p><p>E&amp;T will also have to keep the pressure at equilibrium that way the site doesnt go into melt down</p><p>Once I have a teaser for it i'll post a short sneak peak video :)</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="till-the-next-time">Till the next time<a href="#till-the-next-time" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Till the next time" title="Direct link to Till the next time">​</a></h2><p>That's all for now, as I said the "FAQ" will come out soon as well as the "Currently Working On" page, just want to figure out some of the kinks. Until Thursday (or Saturday, time will tell)</p><p>Have a good evening :)</p><p>-- Aaron Long (Thomastrainiac)</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Long (Thomastrainiac)</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/thomastrainiac</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="development update" term="development update"/>
    </entry>
</feed>